Guide to the Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 1882-1974
Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data
- Series: Lighting 1930-1965
  - Lighting & Productivity, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    Federal Government Study, Public Bldgs. Admin., Dec. 1, 1947
  - Correspondence with Dr. Brenneman on Hawthorne, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Data on Illuminating Engineering Society, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    reprints and correspondence
  - Recommended Levels of Illumination for Industrial Firms, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    Illumination Engineering, Jan. 1956
  - NRECA Lamp Study, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Data on Future Trends in Lighting, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    Illuminating Engineering, June 1959, p.374
  - Intensities of illumination in 10 plants of U.S, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    Factory, Vol. 122 (May 1964), [data on]
  - Better Light - Better Sight Data, correspondence, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Blackwell on Lighting, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - H. Richard Blackwell (Data on Illumination levels) (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlet on Practical Gas Educational Courses - Illumination, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    Gas Lamps, Lesson #7, 1917
  - Data on Phases of the Moon 1925-1928 - use in connection with Hawthorne Studies (Box 13, Folder 29)
    from The American Ephemeris and Nautical Almanac for the year 1925
  - Welsbach Gas Lighting Advertisements, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    in: Lighting Journal, Dec. 1913
  - Alex H. Strecker, "Review of the Report of Dr. S. Rideal on the Hygienic value of Gas & Electric Lighting", 1913 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Society of Gas Lighting, N.Y.C., 3/13/1913
  - Kern Lamp (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Advertisement: Lighting Journal, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    March, 1913 - original
  - American Gas Light Co. "Inverted Gas Avc" Illustration, 1911 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    lots of ads
  - A.E.I.C. Lamp Report, on revenue from Higher Wattage Lamps, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    p. 18
  - Jules Daniels, Illuminating Engineering & the Central Stations, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    presented at Association Island, N.Y., July 23-25, 1923
  - The Supply of Incandescent Lamps to Central Station Customers, Address before the Empire State Gas & Electric Assoc., 1914 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Oct. 2, 1914 by J.W. Lieb [report unfolded]
  - Edison Letters - National Research Coucil (NRC), 1924-1927 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Data related to the role of Thomas A. Edison in the National Research Council Studies into industrial lighting, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    June 6, 1957, signed Charles D. Wrege, [unfolded]
  - Intervale Lighting Test (correspondence with Victor & Little), 1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with John Scott, 1957-1959 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Edward P. Hyde on Hawthorne & General Electric (G.E.), 1957 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Ivanhoe Glassware & Industrial Lighting, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    from Light, Oct. 1925, p.2
  - Clair E. Turner, I Remember, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    on Relay Assembly Test Room (RATR)
  - Charles E. Snow, Introduction to final report on Hawthorne tests (Box 14, Folder 16)
    (never completed), handwritten, 2 pages
  - References to Industrial Lighting Tests in Periodicals, 1925-1930 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Sanford DeHart, "Illumination & Efficiency", 1925 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Industrial Management, (Feb. 1925), Vol. LXIX, No.2, pp.108- 111
  - Harold E. Burtt and The Hawthorne Tests (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 1) 1916 article in Journal of Experimental Psychology (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Vol.1 #2, April 1916
  - 2) Selections from his 1952 book, Applied Psychology (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Negative Photostats of 1924 memorandum on Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Plan book of 1925 Industrial Lighting Campaign (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Letters on National Research Council (NRC) with names of men (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Investigation into Electric Lighting by a Committee of the Society of Gas & Lighting, 1886-1887 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Charles E. Snow, "Illumination Test Summary Test Group, Dept.6325", 1927 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    [1926-1927 Tests, Dated May 2, 1927] (carbon copy)
  - Charles D. Wrege, Production of Test and Control Group "1926-1927 Tests" (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Output 1926-1927 Illumination Tests (Box 14, Folder 26)
    chart
  - Copy of "O" report, 1926-1927 tests (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Snow's Report on 1926-1927 Tests (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Thermofax copy of proposed final report National Research Council (NRC), 1927 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    Charles E. Snow
  - Correspondence from Charles D. Wrege to Willard Allphin, Director Illumination Research Sylvania, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Charles E. Snow, data on "Direct and indirect eyework, in minutes", at Hawthorne (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Photocopy of "O" copy of 1926-1927 Tests (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Analysis of Snow's article in Technicial Engineering News, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Photocopy of 1924-1925 Report of Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Exhibit A - The Industrial Illumination Research, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Copy, presented Nov. 14, 1928 meeting of the National Research Council (NRC) Division of Engineering and Industrial Research (no folder)
  - Photocopy of Report of 1926 Tests at Hawthorne (Box 15, Folder 2)
    16pp
  - tests in Dept. 6325 on 1924-25 tests and 1926 tests, 1924-1926 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Charles E. Snow, handwritten copy
  - National Research Council (NRC) 1924 memorandum (Box 15, Folder 4)
    issued by Dugald C. Jackson on Aug. 26, 1924
  - Independent Study project for Wrege (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Unfolded misc.; by Janet Harris an individual involved in intesity light experiments
  - Schedule of Test Periods, Relay Assembly Test Room, 1927-1930 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Misc. unfolded
  - Western Electric News, "Western Electric Plans Commemoration of Hawthorne Studies" (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Misc. unfolded, no date
  - John Mudroch file, 1924-1928 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Frank Platenka's assistant at Hawthorne 1924-1928 in Main Relay Assembly Department
  - Western Electric [organization] charts (Box 15, Folder 9)
    no date
  - "Bench layout for the assembly of A-1 type relay" (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Tracing of drawing, Xerox copies of drawing
  - "Three to Eleven: a photo Essay on the Second Shift at Hawthorne", 1963 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Article in Western Electric July/Aug. 1963, Vol.XV, No.4, pp. 44-47
  - Correspondence from Western Electric Company on Hawthorne, one with Frank H. Lovette - Archivist (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Mr. J. Walter Deitz on Hawthorne (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Addresses of Dickenson, Roethlesberger & Hibargn in Chicago (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - letter from Mayo to Pennock, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    3/20/28, 5/7/28 & 5/9/28 (carbon copy)
  - Elton Mayo "changing methods in industry", 1930 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Personnel Journal
  - Brech letters, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Dec. 1943
  - Data on Mayo and the Rockefeller Foundation, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Arthur H. Young data (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Empty folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
    empty - material put in Box #16
  - A. H. Ryan Vascular Skin Reaction Test data for NLH (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Binder
  - Death certificate of Mrs. Dwight T. Farnham (Box 15, Folder 22)
    also contains other materials
  - Empty folder (Box 16, Folder 1)
    empty
  - "Earlier Experiments on Employee Performance" (Box 16, Folder 2)
    on Hawthorne Studies from: Supervisory Training Series on Employee Performance, Conference
- Series: R.H. Frazier Hawthorne Experiments 1928-29
  - "An Employee Relations Development Study - Western Electric Co., Inc., Hawthorne Works" (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Frazier, R.H. - 55pp
  - R.H. Frazier - Correspondence 1929-32 with M.L. Putnam re-interview plan for 1928-29 Hawthorne experiment, 1929-1932 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - R.H. Frazier - copies of original interview responses for 1928-29 Hawthorne experiment, 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - Interview program at Hawthorne, 1928-1929 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Data on fatigue (Florence data), and AMA report on Hawthorne fatigue studies (Box 16, Folder 8)
    6pp
  - Fatigue studies charts - operators 2,3,4 (Box 16, Folder 9-11)
    originals and copies
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Mmarked - 1) Photos for Greenwood > Hawthorne & Williamantic Linen Co. 2) Hibarger Photos 3) Mary Pattison (NJ Housekeeping Experiment Station, 1911-12, Colonia, NJ) 4) Consolidated paper photos
  - Copies of Microfilm of original reports & correspondence related to the Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section I - Correspondence related to the initiation of the Committee on Industrial lighting of the National Research Council (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section II - Report on the 1924-25 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section III - Correspondence on the 1924-25 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section IV - Mr. Snow's daily Log for 1925 (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section V - Correspondence on 1926 tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section VI - The report on the 1926 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section VII - Correspondence on the 1926-27 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section VIII - Original report on the 1926-27 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section IX - Official report on the 1926-27 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section X - Progress reports on the 1926-27 Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Section XI -Correspondence related to the Final Meeting of the Committee on Industrial Lighting of the National Research Council (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Charts on Illumination tests (Box 17, Folder 4)
    copies
  - Report to the National Electric Illuminating Society also correspondence with Prof. Munsterberg re: report, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    4/11/14, photocopies